Justin Sena

Justin.Sena44@gmail.com | (916) 667-6392 | Quakertown, PA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data visualization, collection, and management specialist with over 5 years of work experience applying GIS technologies and creative thinking towards the delivery of effective solutions. Ready to take on a position in line with my skills and passion.

WORK HISTORY

Oregon Department of Transportation, Salem, Oregon

Crash Data Technician | 2019 - 2021

- Processed crash data within my 4 counties of responsibility by interpreting driver and police reports and inputting data into the crash database.
- Proactively worked to catch up to same-year reporting by regularly completing over 1.5 times the requested minimum of processed crashes per day.

Placer County, Auburn, California

Intern, Stormwater Quality & Floodplain Mgmt. | 2016 - 2018

- Improved the field data collection process using ESRI products by designing an intuitive and streamlined process that reduced total time spent on annual summer checks by about 1 month.
- Prepared FEMA Flood Risk Maps for individual parcels and region summaries, reporting to the county floodplain manager.
- Digitized infrastructure by georeferencing as-built plans and created approximately 100 floodplain maps for customer requests.

U.S. Navy, USS Blue Ridge/Commander of the 7th Fleet, Yokosuka, Japan *Information Systems Technician | 2009 - 2013*

- Awarded the Navy Achievement Medal for exemplary dedication to my work and for meritorious service.
- Held a Top Secret/SCI security clearance working with satellite communications management for over 100 U.S. Navy ships in the Western Pacific.
- Traveled to 13 countries between Australia and Russia.

SKILLS

- Digital Mapping
- Data Editing
- Web App Development
- Field Data Collection
- Spatial and Network Analysis
- Custom Python Script Tools
- Data Management and Modeling
- ArcGIS Pro and ArcMap expertise
- MS Office Suite

EDUCATION

Oregon State University

Corvallis, OR

2021

B.S. Geog. & Geospatial Science

Sierra College

Rocklin, CA

2018

A.S. Natural Science

<u>2017</u>

GIS Skills Certificate